CARTER ALLEN, PHD



(443) 292-2429 carter.allen12@gmail.com

117 Pocket Bend Cir Summerville SC 29486 United States

PROFILE

I am a **Biostatistician** specializing in the development and application of computational methods for **drug discovery**. I have extensive experience analyzing spatial and single-cell omics, flow cytometry, and high throughput screening data. My guiding motivation is the desire to use statistics and bioinformatics to improve healthcare.

EXPERIENCE

Research Scientist — Statistician, Eli Lilly and Company — 2022 - Present

- Lead the design and analysis of **spatial transcriptomics** experiments to identify drug targets for neurodegenerative and chronic pain conditions
- Develop computation methods and software for automating bottlenecks in drug discovery
- Mentor and manage direct reports, lead cross therapeutic-area collaborations, and orchestrate project deliverables

Graduate Research Associate, The Ohio State University — 2019-2022

- Developed <u>novel statistical and bioinformatic frameworks</u> for spatial transcriptomics
- Served as lead statistician for investigation of <u>novel therapeutic agents for</u> <u>COVID-19</u>

Graduate Research Assistant, Medical University of S.C. -2017-2019

 Developed <u>Bayesian models</u> for clustering and imputation of longitudinal infant development trajectories

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH — PhD in Bioinformatics (2022)

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC — **BS in Statistics** (2017)

SKILLS

Data Science | Bayesian Modeling | Deep Learning | Design of Experiments | Statistical Analysis | Statistical Computation | Single-Cell Data Analysis | Spatial Statistics | R | Python | Software Development